Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection AD.MC.002
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971; 585 (Box 1-7)
  - A couple and a girl. 13.5 x 8.3 cm, 27 January 1926; cuid264; 698; Studio Feldmann, Photo Minia (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Jewelry; Minya, Egypt; Girls; Women; Men; Furnishings; Minia, Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits; Children; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A man seated in a chair wearing a galabeya. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid265; 699; Studio Aida, Abdin (Cairo, Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Men; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A man wearing a uniform, glasses and woolen hat. 14.0 x 9.0 cm, 13 March 1923; cuid266; 700; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Arabic Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Hats; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair
  - Three women in long, dark dresses. 13.7 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid267; 701; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Jewelry; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Furnishings
  - Two women, both wearing hair adornments. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid268; 702; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Women; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - Two women and a girl wearing a cross, sitting on a terrace. 9.2 x 14.7 cm, Undated; cuid269; 703; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Egypt; Religious Crosses; Girls; Women; Children; Parks; Gardens; Group Portraits
  - "Rag day" Students in Pharaonic costumes, raising funds for a hospital. 6.6 x 11.0 cm, 19 February 1927; cuid270; 704; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Photographic Prints; Egypt; English Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Costumes; Charity; Streets/Roads; Students; Hospitals; Street Lamps; Teachers; Schools/Education
  - Two men arm in arm, posing on the street. 13.4 x 8.3 cm, Undated; cuid271; 705; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Streets/Roads; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A man wearing a three-piece suit leaning on a rocky hillside. French text on front "Pour maman". 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid272; 706; Studio A. Foy, Photog, Nice & Royat-les-Bains (France) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Smoking; Nice, France; Cigarettes; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Men; French Writing; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Countryside/Rural; Outdoors; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A hand-painted portrait of a boy wearing a suit and tarbouche. 8.0 x 5.6 cm, Undated; cuid273; 707; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Photographic Prints; Children
  - A young man in a three-piece suit and bow tie, standing in a garden in Yeovil, Somerset. 11.3 x 6.9 cm, 2 August 1925; cuid274; 708; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Photographic Prints; English Writing; Somerset, UK; Bow Ties; Men; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A woman in a long, sleeveless dress, seated next to a girl in a white outfit. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid275; 709; Studio Badr (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Girls; Women; Children; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits; Furnishings
  - A bride and groom with two bridesmaids and flower arrangements. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid276; 710; Studio P. Bastiza, San Stefano, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Weddings; Women; Men; Studio Photography; Group Portraits; Women; Photographic Prints; Weddings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Weddings; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - Three women in clown costumes. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid277; 711; Photo Studio S. M. Adjemian, 19 Boulevard Abbas, Heliopolis (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Costumes; Women; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Group Portraits; Furnishings
  - A family group, seated at a table outside, having a meal. 8.0 x 11.4 cm, Undated; cuid278; 712; Kefalas, F. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Gatherings; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Children; Drinks/Beverages; Furnishings; Men; Women; Food; Facial Hair
  - A building with Islamic architectural features including albaq. 8.8 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid279; 713; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Universities; Buildings
  - Three children, two girls wearing the same dress with bows. 13.3 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid280; 714; Studio Photo Vartian, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Girls; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Boys; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - A family group. 8.8 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid281; 715; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Women; Studio Photography; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - Two children sitting on a block in front of a painted backdrop. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, Undated; cuid282; 716; Studio Photo Ideal, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Alexandria, Egypt; Group Portraits; Furnishings
  - A couple, the man is wearing a suit and has a mustache. 8.3 x 13.5 cm, Undated; cuid283; 717; Studio Photo Cavouk, 53 Rue Choubrah, Cairo, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Cairo, Egypt; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A boy in a Boy Scout uniform. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid284; 718; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Scouts; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Children; Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A young man in a suit and tie looking off camera. Duplicate with different processing effect. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid285; 719; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Men; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A group of men and children at the Colossus of King Ramses II in Memphis, Egypt. 13.9 x 9.0 cm, 1 January 1960; cuid286; 720; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Arabic Writing; Men; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Memphis, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Statues/Sculptures; Boys; Children
  - Two men on a boat called Ramsis. 6.5 x 9.4 cm, Undated; cuid287; 721; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Nile River; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Rivers; Egypt; Facial Hair; Transportation
  - A man on a motorbike holding a baby. 11.5 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid288; 722; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Children; Motorcycles; Streets/Roads; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Transportation
  - Gamal Abdel Nasser and Anwar Sadat, kneeling on the floor (1952-1970). 9.2 x 6.5 cm, Undated; cuid289; 723; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nasser, Gamal Abdel; Sadat, Anwar; Praying; Men; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - Seven women in bathing suits, at the beach. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid330; 763; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Seas; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women; Beaches
  - Three children standing in a doorway, two wearing crosses. 13.4 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid331; 764; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Photographic Prints; Children; Religious Crosses; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Girls; Group Portraits
  - A family group of four sitting on a bench in a park. 8.7 x 13.7 cm, Undated; cuid332; 765; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Women; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Photographic Prints; Parks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits; Children; Boys; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - Three children in front of a painted backdrop. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid333; 766; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Boys; Girls; Studio Photography; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Fezes/Tarbouches; Children; Group Portraits
  - A woman sitting next to a table with a vase on top, resting her feet on a cushion. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid334; 767; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Women; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A man in a suit posing in front of a painted backdrop. Duplicate. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid335; 768; Studio Shahen, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Men; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Tiles
  - A woman wearing a hat and holding a purse (Same woman from ref364). 13.8 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid336; 769; Studio Shahen, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Alexandria, Egypt; Women; Bags/Purses; Hats; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Tiles
  - A woman holding a purse (same woman from ref363). 13.8 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid337; 770; Studio Shahen, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Bags/Purses; Women; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tiles
  - Two young women with short haircuts in white dresses. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid338; 771; Studio Shahen, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Girls; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Clocks/Watches; Group Portraits
  - A couple, the woman is seated on an ornate chair. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid339; 772; Studio C. Rittas, Alexandria (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Painted Backdrops; Men; Head Covers/Veils; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Furnishings; Women; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A family group, two men wearing tarbouches and one woman wearing a light dress. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, 8 June 1917; cuid340; 773; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Group Portraits; Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Fezes/Tarbouches; Arabic Writing; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - A man wearing a tuxedo and tarbouche with a boy, both holding a book. 13.6 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid341; 774; Studio Aziz & Dores, Photographes, 3 Rue de L'Hopital Grec, Alexandrie (Alexandria, Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Men; Boys; Painted Backdrops; Books; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Children; Bow Ties; Tuxedos; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A boy wearing a coat and tarbouche, holding flowers. 13.8 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid342; 775; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Egypt; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Children; Photographic Prints
  - A girl in a white dress with a veil. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid343; 776; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Studio Photography; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Furnishings; Head Covers/Veils; Photographic Prints; Girls; Children
  - Two young women posing in a garden. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid344; 777; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Hats; Bags/Purses; Photographic Prints; Women; Group Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gardens; Outdoors; Clocks/Watches
  - A bride and groom. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, 19 February 1942; cuid345; 778; Studio C. Zaphir, Tantah (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Weddings; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Women; Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Women; Weddings; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Weddings; Studio Photography; Men; Facial Hair
  - A woman looking off camera, with her hands on her hips, in a home setting. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid346; 779; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Furnishings; Egypt; Head Covers/Veils; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Houses
  - A woman with three children standing by a wall. 14.0 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid347; 780; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - A couple posing in their bathing suits at the beach. 13.1 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid348; 781; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Seas; Swimming; Hats; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A group of men, some wearing pith helmets and tarbouches, and a man wearing a Greek Orthodox kamilavkion. 8.7 x 14.2 cm, Undated; cuid349; 782; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Greek Orthodox; Priests/Clergymen; Hats; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair
  - A man with a cane, wearing a tarbouche and a suit. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid350; 783; Studio London Photo, Alexandria, Egypt; Studio London, Cairo, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Hats; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Men; Individual Portraits; Fezes/Tarbouches; Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; Facial Hair
  - A man in a robe, tarbouche and sash with a cresent moon and three stars. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Circa 1922 - 1952; cuid351; 784; London Studio, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Individual Portraits; Men; Flags; Painted Backdrops; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Studio Photography; Academic Dress; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Facial Hair; Medals/Insignia
  - A man in a three-piece suit and a pocket watch. London Studio, Cairo, Egypt. 13.3 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid352; 785; London Studio, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Painted Backdrops; Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair
  - A man in military uniform, holding a sword (linked ref381, ref387, ref388). 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid353; 786; Unknown; Studio Khaled, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Photographic Prints; Gloves; Swords/Knives; Fezes/Tarbouches; Studio Photography; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Egypt; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair; Weapons
  - A man in military uniform and a tarbouche (linked ref380, ref387, ref388). 13.8 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid354; 787; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Studio Photography; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Medals/Insignia; Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair
  - Two women looking off camera, holding hands. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid356; 789; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Women; Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A woman with separated eyelashes, looking off camera. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid357; 790; Studio Photo Jean, Cairo, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Women; Individual Portraits; Cairo, Egypt
  - Two young women, one standing and one sitting, while resting her feet on a cushion. Photo Cleopatra, Suez, Egypt. 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid358; 791; Studio Photo Cleopatra, Suez, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Suez, Egypt; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Women; Group Portraits
  - Two men in tarbouches and suits, resting on a railing. 8.7 x 13.7 cm, Undated; cuid359; 792; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Men; Jewelry; Fezes/Tarbouches; Painted Backdrops; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - Two men and a boy sitting with a book in his hand (linked ref380, ref381, ref388). 13.2 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid360; 793; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Books; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Regional/National Dress; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Men; Studio Photography; Fezes/Tarbouches; Children; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - Three men and a boy. Two men and boy from ref387, with a seated man from ref380 and ref381 in military uniform (linked ref380, ref381, ref387). 13.1 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid361; 794; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Painted Backdrops; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Regional/National Dress; Fezes/Tarbouches; Studio Photography; Men; Group Portraits; Boys; Children; Facial Hair
  - A multi-generational group sitting at a table in restaurant. 8.3 x 14.2 cm, Undated; cuid362; 795; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Restaurants/bars; Fezes/Tarbouches; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Children; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A couple sitting in a park. 8.8 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid363; 796; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Jewelry; Parks; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A studio portrait of a man wearing glasses sitting with a girl wearing a dress. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid364; 797; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Bow Ties; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits
  - A couple posed in front of a window. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid365; 798; Studio Photo London, 26 Boulevard Abbas, Heliopolis (Cairo, Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Men; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A group of two men and three children, sitting on a pavement in front of a park. 8.0 x 13.0 cm, Undated; cuid366; 799; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Egypt; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Boys; Photographic Prints; Girls; Parks; Men; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A group of wheelwrights, making wooden wheels. 8.8 x 12.0 cm, Undated; cuid367; 800; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Workers; Men
  - Two girls wearing matching dresses, with a boy. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid368; 801; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Studio Photography; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Girls; Boys; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Furnishings
  - A ribbon cutting ceremony. 8.7 x 13.7 cm, Undated; cuid369; 802; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Men; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Regional/National Dress; Gelatin Silver Prints; Audiences/Spectators; Crowds; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Events/Occasions; Ceremonies; Fezes/Tarbouches; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A woman with three children, holding a milk bottle. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid370; 803; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Dogs; Painted Backdrops; Children; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Toys; Women; Group Portraits; Animals; Furnishings; Drinks/Beverages
  - A family group, a boy is holding a hoop. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid371; 804; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Children; Facial Hair; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Toys; Boys; Men; Women; Studio Photography; Group Portraits; Furnishings
  - A man in military uniform and a tarbouche. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, 12 December 1939; cuid372; 805; Studio Photo Sarkis, Assiout, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Photographic Prints; Asyut, Egypt; Men; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Swords/Knives; Studio Photography; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Weapons; Medals/Insignia; Carpets/Rugs; Weapons
  - A man in a military uniform holding a cane. 14.1 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid373; 806; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Uniforms; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Fezes/Tarbouches; Navy; Canes/Walking Sticks; Military/Soldiers
  - Four women on a swan carousel, with a flag of Egypt (1923-1952) in the background. 8.2 x 11.0 cm, cuid374; 807; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Buildings; Egypt; Flags; Women; Photographic Prints; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Group Portraits
  - A man with three boys in matching outfits and a girl sitting in a chair. 13.9 x 9.1 cm, Undated; cuid375; 808; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Girls; Boys; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Fezes/Tarbouches; Painted Backdrops; Children; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - A man and a woman posing in a Bedouin costume, the man holds a sword and a gun, and the woman holds a water pot. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid376; 809; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Men; Studio Photography; Costumes; Weapons; Swords/Knives; Guns; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Tiles; Carpets/Rugs; Pottery; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Furnishings
  - An elderly woman in a garden with a flower in her hand. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid377; 810; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Women; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Gardens; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
  - A man wearing a bowler hat standing in a park, with a bird on his right arm. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid378; 811; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Animals; Egypt; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Parks; Birds; Men
  - A boy posing as a Greek soldier. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid379; 812; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Children; Boys; Costumes; Weapons; Regional/National Dress; Guns; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints
  - A man wearing a sash resting on a tall side table. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, 31 October 1914; cuid380; 813; K. Jacob, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Studio Photography; Fezes/Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Men; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - A boy with a doll, standing on some stairs. 13.4 x 8.5 cm, 1936; cuid381; 814; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Children; Boys; Hats; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Toys
  - A girl wearing a sequined dress kneeling on a leopard skin rug. 13.3 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid382; 815; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Individual Portraits; Girls; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Carpets/Rugs
  - A woman resting on a folding screen. Signed by the same person as ref411, Elise Bruno. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid383; 816; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 16)